Vinod Karantothu



vinod.karantothu@live.in



+91 9000700297



linkedin.com/in/karantothu

Summary

Highly-skilled and motivated software engineer with 2.5 years of total experience, 2 years in developing Camera Al and Video Analytics software applications.

Experienced Python developer with strong skills in Flask, Django, REST-API.

Experienced in creating Docker Containers leveraging existing Linux Containers and containerising the Python applications.

Experience



Senior Software Developer

ZestIoT: IoT/AI powered connected operations platform

Jul 2021 - Present (11 months +)

Working on developing NoCode AI Computer Vision platform focused on automating the tedious and repetitive code development needed for any computer vision model.

Tech Stack: Linux, Docker, Python, Flask, RabbitMQ, Redis, OpenCV, MySQL, Nginx

Software Developer

ZestIoT: IoT/AI powered connected operations platform

Aug 2020 - Jun 2021 (11 months)

Developed edge application for Camera AI products.

Tech Stack: Linux(Raspbian), Python, Flask, HTML, Bootstrap, MQTT, Nginx

Software Development Intern

Corteva Agriscience

Jun 2019 - Feb 2020 (9 months)

Developed REST APIs using Python, Flask, and Web UI with Angular 5 for GeneFamily (GFam 3.0), a bioinformatics tool to search and analyse gene and protein data.

Tech Stack: Python, Flask, MySQL, and Angular. REST API, AWS: EC2, S3.

Microsoft Student Partner

Microsoft

Nov 2015 - Jan 2017 (1 year 3 months)

One of the on-campus student ambassadors to lead the student tech community and develop technical and career skills for the future.

Tech: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals.

Education

Blekinge Institute of Technology

Master of Science (M.Sc.), Software Engineering 2017 - 2019 ECTS: 90/120

Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University

Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.), Computer Science 2013 - 2017

Licenses & Certifications

Codility Golden Award (Future Mobility) - Codility Issued Sep 2018 - Expires Sep 2022

FPGA Based Embedded Systems Covering Swadeshi Microprocessors NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF ELECTRONICS & INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY
(NIELIT)
IEP-OLC 2594

Skills

Python (Programming Language) • Flask • Django • Django REST Framework • Linux • Ubuntu • RabbitMQ • Redis • Docker Products • Amazon Web Services (AWS)